

ÓLAFUR ARON JÓHANNSSON DEVELOPER

27 years old developer with 5 years of professional experience in software development. Started programming 7 years ago.

Father of two boys, interested in marathon running, exercising, playing guitar, music theory, software development, design, books and video games.

- EMPLOYMENT

2016- Divot ehf

Software Developer

Icelandic company that services Venuepoint A/S.

2013-2015 Venuepoint A/S

Software Developer

Besides my daily tasks as a Developer, i took part in implementing continuous integration of our software stack in development and staging. Defining automatic testing and delivery of static content to CDN servers. I helped set up and defined Agile principles. Introduced git and its practices using a branch workflow that I taught to our developers. Used to being a team lead in big projects.

2013 Reykjavík University

Teaching Assistant

Teaching lab classes in Web Programming. Using ASP.NET MVC, C#, JavaScript, HTML/CSS and MS SQL.

2012 Live Shuttle ehf

Software Developer

Took part in the Startup Reykjavík Incubator and got funding to initiate a startup with a friend. The idea never got momentum but the experience earned was invaluable.

2011-2013 Þekking hf

IT Specialist / Software Developer

My main duties involved software development. My clients were the Museum of Iceland where I maintained a CRUD system used by all museums in Iceland called Sarpur and the Ministry of Finance, where I was part of the team that releases the fiscal budget. My duties was putting content on the web and everything technical.

7

Website

www.olafurjohannsson.com www.github.com/olafurjohannsson



Mobile (+354) 655-7838



Email

olafur@johannsson.co

EDUCATION

2012- Computer Science - B.Sc.

Reykjavík University, 90 ECTS completed Administrator of Programming Contest

2009-2011 Information Technology

Technical College Reykjavík

Contestant in Programming Content

2011 Promennt

MCTS - WCF Development with .NET 4 MCTS - Accessing Data with .NET 4

+ PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

average good skilled

Development

Agile

Design

Project management

SCM

C#
Node
Python
C/C++
Go
JavaScript
HTML/CSS
SQL

Favorite language Python

Most skilled C#

Guilty pleasure JavaScript

Currently learning Swift/RabbitMq

+ PERSONAL SKILLS

average good skilled

Communication

Problem solving

Determination

Team Player

Responsibility

+ REFERENCES

References can be supplied on request.

Freelance / Presentations / Work in progress

2016 Guardian (alpha)

Parental control software that uses pcap to monitor network traffic on multiple devices and aggregate data to a web frontend. Still in prototype phase but so far I'm using Go/Python/C#/RabbitMQ/Redis and PostgreSQL

2015- www.quickinvoice.is

 A project built using Node with Typescript, Angular, SASS/HTML, Redis and PostgreSQL. It creates Icelandic compatible invoices. Closedsource. The package that converts invoices to PDFs is open-sourced:

www.npmjs.com/package/htmltopdf

 It's hosted in Digital Ocean on a Debian server with nginx as a reverse proxy and uses Codeship for continuous integration and automatic testing.
 Mocha, chai and mockery are used for unit-tests.

2015 www.wokon.is

Built this website for a restaurant that is opening soon. It's hosted on my own servers in Digital Ocean. Only static HTML/CSS on nginx.

2015- endurskodun.johannsson.co

A website in progress for an accounting firm, hosted on nginx with only static content HTML/CSS and JS.

2015- valkyrja.johannsson.co

A white label AliExpress/Amazon site in progress that targets specific focus groups. Using Python and Twisted.

2014- Leiðir ehf

- Programmed against Nayax VPOS using C++, Java and C#. The communication channel was serial ports.
- Built an ASMX Web Service as the payment and access right portal that the POS peripheral used for communication.
- Built an auto-backup application that takes copies
 of sensitive data across distributed servers and
 backups to servers that fulfill a interface defined by
 the job.

2014 Art of programming

Did a presentation in the Innovation house on the art of programming, the focus group was beginners. http://slides.com/olafurj/the-art-of-programming

2013 Kaptio ehf

Minor freelancing jobs for this startup. Mainly using SalesForce with Java and Python 2.7 scripting, such as lookups in Hjartavernd via social security.

2012 Startup Reykjavík

Took part in the Incubator Startup Reykjavík with a startup in 2012, where the experience gained was immense.